<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>business on Arjun Uvacha</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/categories/business/</link>
        <description>Recent content in business on Arjun Uvacha</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 13:42:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.arjunuvacha.com/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>RRR&#39;s Naatu Naatu is moments away from creating history!</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/rrr/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 13:42:24 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/rrr/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/rrr/RRR-at-Oscars.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post RRR&#39;s Naatu Naatu is moments away from creating history!" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;indian-cinema-at-the-oscars&#34;&gt;Indian Cinema at the Oscars&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the clock strikes 5:30 AM on 13th March 2023 (IST), India would be making history. And the James Gordon (from the Dark Knight) in me would say, &lt;em&gt;“This is what we deserve. Not what we need.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its 110-year-long cinematic journey, it is disheartening to know that a mere 4 ‘Indian’ productions have secured Oscar nominations and NEVER won the coveted award, despite being the second largest film industry in the world in the 1950s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been glimmers of recognition in the past but Indian Cinema was majorly ‘unnoticed’ by the outside world until recently. And the worldview of Indian Cinema is changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after a good 21 years of Amir Khan’s Lagaan, when the team RRR shows up at the Oscars I can’t cheer and scream enough! I can’t wait for the event to unfold and root for our home team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been a few Indian representatives at the Oscars in the past but they were majorly under ‘international’ productions. And a handful of Indians even won the award: &lt;strong&gt;Bhanu Athaiya, Satyajit Ray, AR Rahman, and Resul Pookutty&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;‘Indian’&lt;/strong&gt; films saw a total of 3 nominations for Best International Feature Film and 1 nomination for Best Documentary Feature so far in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though there have been Indian representations at the Oscars in the past - this time is very very different!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s why this is such a significant moment for all of us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rrr---a-game-changer&#34;&gt;RRR - a Game Changer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-indian-movie&#34;&gt;First Indian Movie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RRR is the first ‘Indian movie’ produced by an Indian production house, DVV Entertainment, to be nominated for Best Original Song (‘Naatu Naatu’).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(RRR missed its coveted chance for Best International Feature Film - blame Indian Film Council if you want for not sending it!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;huge-market-potential&#34;&gt;Huge market potential&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would open up a HUGE movie market in the West (and the East!). A lot of new avenues have already been broke open, thanks to SS Rajamouli, but there’s still a long way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total movie market (theater biz) is more than $42bn. India currently stands at 5th position:&lt;br&gt;
US: $10.5bn&lt;br&gt;
China: $9.3bn&lt;br&gt;
Japan: $2.4bn&lt;br&gt;
France: $1.62bn&lt;br&gt;
India: $1.6bn&lt;br&gt;
South Korea: ~1.6bn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other major markets beyond these regions, including UK, UAE etc which account to about $7.1bn where Indian movies are actively screened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the box office numbers of all the countries &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://flixpatrol.com/market/box-office-revenues/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, RRR could become a golden pass for other upcoming Indian movies to capture a piece of a potential $32bn movie market, if it wins the award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;increased-budgets-for-upcoming-indian-movies&#34;&gt;Increased budgets for upcoming Indian movies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could also mean increase in both the size of budgets and number of big budget movies coming from India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average budget of top 10 most expensive Hollywood movies is a staggering $388mn! In comparison, top 10 Indian movies average at a dismal $45mn - offering a significant gap for increasing investments and making bigger movies. So, the large production houses are bound to get influenced by the Oscars result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;access-to-global-talent&#34;&gt;Access to global talent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the budget and box office numbers don’t excite you, if you are more of an ‘art’ person than a ‘commerce’ person, then - RRR winning Oscar could open doors to access global talent, from actors to actresses to technicians for the Indian filmmakers, that could lead to high quality films coming from India!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-phenomenon-called-ss-rajamouli&#34;&gt;The phenomenon called SS Rajamouli&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From drawing people across the country, SS Rajamouli is now in a different league. His RRR has grossed INR 1200 Cr already, has garnered so much attention, love and thumping response from audience around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The audience filled the theatres completely whenever the movie was screened in the US - setting up a record of getting sold out in a mere 98 seconds when the tickets were opened for booking in a 932 seater TCL’s Chinese Theatre in LA. Also, the movie is the highest grossing Indian movie in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;awards-for-rrr&#34;&gt;Awards for RRR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has received multiple awards including from Hollywood Critics Association, LA Film Critics Association Awards, New York Film Critics Circle Awards, Dada Saheb Phalke Film Festival, Hawaii Film Critics Society, Kansas City Film Critics Awards, and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check all the awards &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt8178634/awards/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having won the Golden Globes and Critics Choice Awards beating the likes of Rihanna, Lady Gaga and Taylor Swift, the chances of winning the Oscars too are very high! And this will be a game changer if RRR wins the award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wishing SS Rajamouli, NTR Jr, Ram Charan, MM Keeravani, Pre Rakshit, Chandrabose, Rahul Sipligunj, Kaala Bhairava and the entire team the best of luck for tomorrow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all would be rooting for you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are other nominations this year:
Kartiki Gonsalves&amp;rsquo;s The Elephant Whisperers, Shaunak Sen&amp;rsquo;s touching All That Breathes. But it is RRR that is taking away all the media light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a movie buff like me, you can watch it live on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hotstar.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Disney+ Hotstar&lt;/a&gt; in India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! Check out my other articles too&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
