<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Pages on Arjun Uvacha</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/page/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Pages on Arjun Uvacha</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 23:29:12 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.arjunuvacha.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Privacy Policy</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/privacy-policy/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 23:29:12 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/privacy-policy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Updated and Effective: Jan 23, 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-privacy-policy&#34;&gt;About Privacy Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog, Arjun Uvacha (“Arjun Uvacha”, “the blog”, “the website”, “the product”, “the site”, “the platform”, “we”), is a personal blog maintained by K Harish Arjun (“owner”, “I”, “me”, “my”, myself”). The thoughts, views, ideas, comments, rhetorics, observations, remarks, opinions, reflections, judgements and discussions are my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Privacy Policy is applicable to data subjects within the European Economic Area (“EEA”). Therefore, this Policy is drafted to comply with the E.U. General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (“GDPR”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of compliance with the GDPR, we are the data controller of information we collect from data subjects through the Services. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, “data subject” means an identified or identifiable natural person located in the EEA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless we link to a different policy or state otherwise, this Privacy Policy applies when you visit or use the website or related services (the “Services”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By using the Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.&lt;/strong&gt; We strongly encourage you to read and understand our terms. You shouldn’t use the website if you don’t agree with this Privacy Policy or any other agreement that governs your use of the Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-collection&#34;&gt;Information Collection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not collect any personal information or personal data directly from the user visiting the website. We collect some data automatically, like information about your device and what parts of our Services you interact with or spend time using.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parts of the Services let you post comments or participate in discussions on the website publicly, including by asking or answering questions. Such shared content is collected and may be publicly viewable by others depending on where it is posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you access or use our Services through a third-party platform or service, or click on any third-party links, the collection, use, and sharing of your data will also be subject to the privacy policies and other agreements of that third party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-usage&#34;&gt;Information Usage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website respects the privacy of its visitors. The website is published on Google’s Ad network and no personal information of any user is passed directly from the website to Google Ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;communications-and-support&#34;&gt;Communications and Support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you contact us for support or to report a problem or concern, we collect and store your contact information, messages, and other data about you like your name, email address, and any other data you provide or that we collect through automated means. We use this data to respond to you and research your question or concern, in accordance with this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contact-data&#34;&gt;Contact Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Includes contact details which we gather in order to communicate information to you regarding our Services, like location, email address, and phone number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you access the Services (including browsing courses), we collect certain data by automated means, including&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;system-data&#34;&gt;System Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical data about your computer or device, like your IP address, device type, operating system type and version, unique device identifiers, browser, browser language, domain and other systems data, and platform types (“System Data”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;usage-data&#34;&gt;Usage Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usage statistics about your interactions with the Services, including courses accessed, time spent on pages or the Service, pages visited, features used, your search queries, click data, date and time, and other data regarding your use of the Services (“Usage Data”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;approximate-and-geographic-data&#34;&gt;Approximate and Geographic Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An approximate geographic location, including information like country, city, and geographic coordinates, is calculated based on your IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-get-data-about-you&#34;&gt;How We Get Data About You?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use tools like web cookies, web beacons, analytics services, and advertising providers to gather the various categories of data listed above. Some of these tools offer you the ability to opt out of data collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-collect-personal-information-from-you-when-you&#34;&gt;We collect Personal Information from you when you:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interact with us on various social media channels such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, etc.;
Post information to the Site or Services that includes Personal Information, for example, by posting in the comments section of the website or on a blog post;
Communicate with us, for example, by submitting queries regarding the Site or Services,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cookies-and-data-collection-tools&#34;&gt;Cookies and Data Collection Tools&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Service providers acting on our behalf (like Google Analytics, Google Ads) use server log files and automated data collection tools like cookies, tags, scripts, customized links, device or browser fingerprints, and web beacons (together, “Data Collection Tools”) when you access and use the Services. These Data Collection Tools automatically track and collect certain System Data and Usage Data (as detailed in the previous Section) when you use the Services. In some cases, we tie data gathered through those Data Collection Tools to other data that we collect as described in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use cookies (small files that websites send to your device to uniquely identify your browser or device or to store data in your browser) for things like analyzing your use of the Services, personalizing your experience, and recognizing you when you return. We use web beacons (small objects that allow us to measure the actions of visitors and users using the Services) for things like identifying whether a page was visited and advertising more efficiently by excluding current users from certain promotional messages or identifying the source of a new mobile app download.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;analytics&#34;&gt;Analytics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use third-party browsers and mobile analytics services like Google Analytics on the Services. These services use Data Collection Tools to help us analyze your use of the Services, including information like the third-party website you arrive from, how often you visit, events within the Services, and usage and performance data. We use this data to improve the Services, better understand how the Services perform on different devices and provide information that may be of interest to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-advertising&#34;&gt;Online Advertising&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use third-party advertising services like Google’s ad services to deliver advertising about our Services on other websites and applications you use. The ads may be based on things we know about you, like your Usage Data and System Data (as detailed in Section 1), and things that these ad service providers know about you based on their tracking data. The ads can be based on your recent activity or activity over time and across other sites and services and may be tailored to your interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the types of advertising services we use, they may place cookies or other tracking technologies on your computer, phone, or other devices to collect data about your use of our Services, and may access those tracking technologies in order to serve these tailored advertisements to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-we-use-your-data&#34;&gt;How We Use Your Data?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may use your Personal Information for lawful purposes as required by law. We use your data to do things like provide our Services, communicate with you, troubleshoot issues, secure against fraud and abuse, improve and update our Services, analyze how people use our Services, serve personalized advertising, and as required by law or necessary for safety and integrity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use the data we collect through your use of the Services to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide and administer the Services, including to display customized content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate with you about your account by responding to your questions and concerns and solicit feedback from the users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn more about yourself by linking your data with additional data through third-party data providers or analyzing the data with the help of analytics service providers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify unique users across devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tailor advertisements across devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve our Services and develop new products, services, and features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze trends and traffic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advertise the Services on third-party websites and applications&lt;br&gt;
As required or permitted by law or as we, in our sole discretion, otherwise determine to be necessary to ensure the safety or integrity of our users, employees, third parties, the public, or our Services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-we-share-your-data-with&#34;&gt;Who We Share Your Data With?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We share certain data about you with advertising companies who use this data to offer you targeted ad delivery to personalize your user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-rights&#34;&gt;Your Rights&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a data subject located in the EEA, the GDPR grants you certain data privacy rights. You have certain rights with respect to your Personal Information, including the:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right to request access to the information that we hold about you and the reasons for which we are processing your information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right to request that your information be rectified where it is incorrect or incomplete by contacting us at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:harisharjun.online&amp;#43;arjunuvacha@gmail.com&#34; &gt;harisharjun.online+arjunuvacha@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. We will comply with the requirements of data protection law when handling your request&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right to delete the information we hold about you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right to object to data processing (including in instances where processing is based on legitimate interests or for marketing purposes)&lt;br&gt;
To exercise your rights, please contact us at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:harisharjun.online&amp;#43;arjunuvacha@gmail.com&#34; &gt;harisharjun.online+arjunuvacha@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. We will comply with the requirements of applicable data protection laws when handling your request. Please be aware that your rights are limited to the extent permitted by the GDPR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-choices-about-the-use-of-your-data&#34;&gt;Your Choices About the Use of Your Data&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The browser or device you use may allow you to control cookies and other types of local data storage. Your wireless device may also allow you to control whether location or other data is collected and shared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get information and control cookies used for tailored advertising from participating companies, see the consumer opt-out pages for the Network Advertising Initiative and Digital Advertising Alliance, or if you’re located in the European Union, visit the Your Online Choices. To opt out of Google’s display advertising or customize Google Display Network ads, visit the Google Ads Settings Page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To opt out of allowing Google Analytics to use your data for analytics or enrichment, see the Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-On.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about your data, our use of it, or your rights, contact us at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:harisharjun.online&amp;#43;arjunuvacha@gmail.com&#34; &gt;harisharjun.online+arjunuvacha@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;our-policy-concerning-children&#34;&gt;Our Policy Concerning Children&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We recognize the privacy interests of children and encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. Children under 13 (or under 16 in the European Economic Area) should not use the Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parents or guardians who believe that Arjun Uvacha may have collected Personal Information from a child under those ages can submit a request that it be removed to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:harisharjun.online&amp;#43;arjunuvacha@gmail.com&#34; &gt;harisharjun.online+arjunuvacha@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-not-track-disclosure&#34;&gt;Do Not Track Disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some internet browsers may transmit “do-not-track” signals to websites with which the browser communicates. The Site does not currently respond to these “do-not-track” signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;third-party-links&#34;&gt;Third-Party Links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Services may contain links to other websites or applications (“Linked Sites”) that are not owned by Arjun Uvacha. We do not control the collection or use of any information, including Personal Information, which occurs while you visit Linked Sites. Therefore, we make no representations or warranties for—and will not in any way be liable for—any content, products, services, software, or other materials available on Linked Sites, even if one or more pages of the Linked Site are framed within a page of the Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, we make no representations or warranties about the privacy policies or practices of the Linked Sites, and the Company is not responsible for the privacy practices of those Linked Sites. We encourage you to be aware of when you leave the Site and read the privacy policies of Linked Sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updates-to-this-policy&#34;&gt;Updates to this policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11.1 Modifications to This Privacy Policy
From time to time, we may update this Privacy Policy. Modifications will become effective on the day they are posted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As permitted by applicable law, if you continue to use the Services after the effective date of any change, then your access and/or use will be deemed an acceptance of (and agreement to follow and be bound by) the revised Privacy Policy. The revised Privacy Policy supersedes all previous Privacy Policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact-information-and-how-to-file-a-complaint&#34;&gt;Contact Information and How to File a Complaint&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contact-us&#34;&gt;Contact Us&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, concerns, or disputes regarding our Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact me using: Email: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:harisharjun.online&amp;#43;arjunuvacha@gmail.com&#34; &gt;harisharjun.online+arjunuvacha@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cookies&#34;&gt;Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are cookies?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Cookies are small text files stored by your browser as you browse the internet. They can be used to collect, store, and share data about your activities across websites, including on Arjun Uvacha Services. Cookies also allow us to remember things about your visits to Arjun Uvacha Services, like your preferred language, and to make the site easier to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use both session cookies, which expire after a short time or when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which remain stored in your browser for a set period of time. We use session cookies to identify you during a single browsing session, like when you log into Arjun Uvacha Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why does Arjun Uvacha use cookies and similar technologies?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
We use cookies and similar technologies like web beacons, pixel tags, or local shared objects (“flash cookies”), to deliver, measure, and improve our services in various ways. We use these cookies when you visit our site and services through a browser. As we adopt additional technologies, we may also gather additional data through other methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use cookies for the following purposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To remember data about your browser and your preferences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To remember your settings and other choices you’ve made
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example, cookies help us remember your preferred language or the country you’re in, so we can provide content in your preferred language without asking each time you visit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytics and Research
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To help us improve and understand how people use Arjun Uvacha Services
For example, cookies help us test different versions of Arjun Uvacha to see which features or content users prefer, web beacons help us determine which email messages are opened, and cookies help us see how you interact with Arjun Uvacha’s Services, like the links you click on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We also work with analytics partners, including Google Analytics, who use cookies and similar technologies to help us analyze how users use the Services, including by noting the sites from which you arrive. Those service providers may either collect that data themselves or we may disclose it to them. You can opt out of some of these services through tools like the Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-On.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advertising
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide you with more relevant advertising&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please note that where advertising technology is integrated into the Services, you may still receive advertising on other websites and applications, but it will not be tailored to your interests. To learn more about targeting and advertising cookies and how you can opt-out, visit Www.Allaboutcookies.Org/Manage-Cookies/Index.Html, or if you’re located in the European Union, visit the Your Online Choices Site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are my privacy options?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
You have a number of options to control or limit how we and our partners use cookies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your browser settings to decline cookies by consulting your browser’s support articles. If you decide to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in, customize, or use some interactive features in the Services.
Flash cookies operate differently than browser cookies, so your browser’s cookie-management tools may not remove them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get information and control cookies used for tailored advertising from participating companies, see the consumer opt-out pages for the Network Advertising Initiative and Digital Advertising Alliance, or if you’re located in the European Union, visit the Your Online Choices Site. To opt out of Google Analytics’ display advertising or customize Google Display Network ads, visit the Google Ads Settings Page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For general information about targeting cookies and how to disable them, visit Allaboutcookies.Org.
Updates &amp;amp; Contact Info&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about our use of cookies, please email us at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:harisharjun.online&amp;#43;arjunuvacha@gmail.com&#34; &gt;harisharjun.online+arjunuvacha@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Archives</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/archives/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/archives/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>About</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/about/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/about/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://www.arjunuvacha.com/sky.jpg" alt="Featured image of post About" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arjun Uvacha&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (/ˈɜːʤʊn ʊwɒʧɑː/)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arjun Uvacha&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a Sanskrit phrase which simply translates to &amp;lsquo;Arjun said&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Arjun spoke&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phrase gains significance from the Hindu scripture &amp;lsquo;Bhagavad Gita&amp;rsquo;, in which the troubled and curious Arjuna inquires Lord Krishna about what to do before the epic war of Kurukshetra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dialogues between the Lord Krishna (the one imparting the Knowledge) and Arjuna (the one seeking the Knowledge) are exchanged. These dialogues are represented in the scriptures as &amp;lsquo;Krishna Uvacha&amp;rsquo; (Krishna Said&amp;hellip;) and &amp;lsquo;Arjuna Uvacha&amp;rsquo; (Arjuna Said&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a Product Manager, I too ask many questions, to myself and many other &amp;lsquo;Krishnas&amp;rsquo;, I meet in my journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answers to these questions could be as simple to understand as a yes or a no or could take a life experience to realise the intricacies and the complexities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how easy or difficult the answer is, it is the curiousity and the perennial pursuit to seek the truth that is of paramount importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping that spirit of curiosity at the center, in this blog, I try and pen down the questions I have asked myself, and others. And if the pursuit of truth is relentless, I think, the answers will follow, and I will add them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thus the name for this blog!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;../&#34; &gt;Continue to the blog&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am Arjun, a product manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is rather inconspicuous how our behaviours are shaped. They make us do certain things in a certain way; and the role of products around us in shaping our behaviours is compelling, which has always fascinated me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here I am, trying my bit to build better products, for &lt;strong&gt;Good!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;find-me-on&#34;&gt;Find me on:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/harisharjun/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/harisharjun&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/arjunuvacha_&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; •  &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://clubhouse.com/@arjunuvacha&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt; • &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/arjunuvacha/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Search</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/search/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/search/</guid>
        <description></description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
