<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>habits on Arjun Uvacha</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/tags/habits/</link>
        <description>Recent content in habits on Arjun Uvacha</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 15:40:53 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.arjunuvacha.com/tags/habits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Every setback is an opportunity to reset</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/every-setback-is-an-opportunity-to-reset/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 15:40:53 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/every-setback-is-an-opportunity-to-reset/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/every-setback-is-an-opportunity-to-reset/harish-arjun-reset.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Every setback is an opportunity to reset" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-setback&#34;&gt;The setback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, I was asked to leave my previous organisation. I was one of the 1000s who were affected by the layoffs across the globe, across all kinds of organisations - from leading tech giants like Google and Facebook to established startups like mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was thoroughly enjoying my role as a Senior Product Manager at Phable Care, building some kickass products for the doctors on our platform. But, unfortunately, I was asked to leave as the company was not able to secure its series C funding. And I was not alone. About 50 others also were asked to leave along with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a sad feeling. You work so hard building something, and right when the foundation is just laid, you are asked to leave. All your hopes of doing something great get shattered just like that, in a moment. You think, ‘another setback in life.’ And you don’t have any other option but to accept the new reality and move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I moved on and it’s been a month so far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-really-a-setback&#34;&gt;Not really a setback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was told that I was being fired, I knew that there was nothing worrisome about it and that I would figure something out sooner or later. So, I didn’t whine or stare into the empty wall pitying myself or curse the company for shattering my hopes. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do any of that. After all, it was just a temporary halt in a much longer journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not immediately set out looking for another opportunity. I had gone through the job search journey a couple of times already in the past and knew that it would need a lot of rigour, persistence and hard work to crack a good one again. Yet I was not perturbed. It did not bother me that I had lost my job and would probably be jobless for a month or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt it was ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could have been partly because of my wife. She is employed by the Government and has a stable job. So, that definitely gave me a lot of confidence and I knew that nothing would break down if my salary doesn&amp;rsquo;t get credited for a couple of months. I knew I would always have her support which was reassuring. So, thanks to her for giving me that confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But keeping the financial security aside, there were a few other factors that helped me keep my calm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-much-needed-break&#34;&gt;A much needed break&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think one major reason was I personally wanted to take a break and slow down because so many things were happening very fast and I wasn’t able to be &lt;strong&gt;there fully&lt;/strong&gt; in those moments. I didn’t particularly want to rush into things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Many times, you get so immersed in what you are doing and what lies ahead that you miss out on so many wonderful moments happening around you. You don’t seem to have ‘time’ to enjoy them fully.&amp;rdquo; That happened to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of things got changed in the past year - I got married, was occupied with a lot of post-marriage customs till recently, vacated my house in Bengaluru, changed my job, my wife got selected as a Deputy Collector in Andhra Pradesh, we moved from Chennai to Guntur, we constantly travelled to many places - for work and for personal trips and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these were significant events in their own way. I was not overwhelmed by them, but they definitely kept me busy. These were in addition to the already hectic office work. So, when the office work was officially ‘called off,’ some part of me definitely felt like, ‘Oh wow!’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe, I just needed a break and the layoff was a blessing in disguise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What break did I need anyway? Break from what?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This did not mean taking a break from doing anything or a break time where I wanted to simply lie down and do nothing or watch a dozen movies and a handful of series and chill out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably would have been more frustrated if I had to take such a break where I did nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;break-from-what&#34;&gt;Break from what?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking at this break as a trigger to slow down, clean up the clutter, separate the music from the noise, and figure out a meaningful way in the chaos. &amp;ldquo;This seemed like a setback, but could I use this as a prompt to reset a few things?&amp;rdquo; I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also knew that I was not being my best self over the past year. I wanted to do many things for a very long time but could not do them - mainly because I was either caught up with work or was just plain lazy. I used to complete my office work and just relax for the rest of the time… That was not satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the past month of having time for myself was really a boon, a blessing that helped me get back to the things that I wanted to do for a very long time. It gave me a sense of fulfilment that I missed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-few-things-helped-me-gain-myself&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few things helped me gain myself.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-changed-my-routine&#34;&gt;I changed my routine.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staying up late in the night watching a movie or doing some work was a normal thing. But when I was asked to leave Phable I realised that I would have more time at my disposal and that it was an opportunity to change my routine. So, I started sleeping early and waking up early. This was a welcome change that I wanted for so long which wouldn’t have happened if not for the layoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-practised-meditation-again&#34;&gt;I practised meditation again.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I practised meditation regularly since my 7th grade but that wasn’t the case in the past 3-4 years. I stopped practising meditation completely. But, in the past, I had experienced that meditation made me calmer, more productive, and more creative. The layoff gave me that extra push to practise meditation again and I have now made it a point to meditate for 15-20min every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;completed-reading-3-books&#34;&gt;Completed reading 3 books.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2020, during the pandemic, I saved some time as there was no need to travel to the office due to the lockdown. In that extra time, I started reading books. But over the past 2 years, though I was predominantly working from home, the habit of reading books faded gradually. But thanks to the layoff, I was able to get back to reading again. I completed reading 3 books so far and wish to read at least 6 books every year. This doesn’t seem like a huge goal, so I am hopeful that I will be able to meet this goal every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;revived-my-blog&#34;&gt;Revived my blog.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this blog in 2021. I learnt how to set up a blog for almost free of cost, explored some blogging tech stacks and figured out what would work best for me. It took some time to set this up, but I did it - I used the Hugo framework for content management and hosted it on Firebase. Setting it up was fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though the blog was set up, it was not complete. There were still some minor issues which required more attention from me. Unfortunately even that did not happen in the last 2 years. Thanks to the layoff, I was able to fix the blog too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;started-publishing-again&#34;&gt;Started publishing again.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actively wrote about product management, user behaviour, and some personal stories when I started blogging back in 2021. Writing gave me joy and a sense of fulfilment. It was an avenue for me to do something creative and give life to my imagination. This was missing in my life and I badly wanted to start writing again. Thanks to the layoff, I was able to get back to writing again and I couldn’t be happier. I published 4 articles since the layoff and plan to publish 50 this year! Long way to go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;got-google-adsense-approval-for-my-blog&#34;&gt;Got Google Adsense approval for my blog.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being an entrepreneur at heart, I was always excited about any prospect of creating something from scratch. The blog was one such endeavour in a way. I wanted to take the blog to the next level. I explored different ways and found that I could join the Google Publishers Network through Adsense. I applied for Google Adsense then, in 2021, and it was rejected! I applied again but it was rejected again. I applied for the third time and got rejected again. I got frustrated and stopped applying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to 2023, I made some changes to the blog structure and gave it another shot - only to get rejected again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I was very stubborn this time- the layoff probably gave me wings! I spent a lot of time reading on Quora and watching videos on how to get approval. I then made some more changes to the blog and applied again. And after 2 weeks of a long wait, the blog was approved for Adsense. It felt amazing… like achieving something great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The happiness you get from earning money from something that you have built from scratch is unmatched. Though very tiny (at the moment) compared to the salary as a Product Manager, it gives me a great sense of fulfilment! Thanks to the layoff again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;got-my-car-license&#34;&gt;Got my car license.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first paid the fee for my 4-wheeler driving license in 2016. Yes, 7 years ago. But that was in vain as I just did not give the driving test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past 7 years, this was such a constant quibble in my head that I doubted myself. There was this regret about not completing something that I had started which was not even difficult or impossible. But when I applied for the license again recently, I finally got over that regret. I have the license now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might seem such a small thing but, sometimes, it is these small things which you were not able to accomplish for so long that once you accomplish them, you feel liberated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;created-an-online-resume&#34;&gt;Created an online resume.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stand out in my job search, I created an online resume for myself: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://arjunuvacha.com/k-harish-arjun-resume&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Resume link&lt;/a&gt;. This is helping me showcase myself better and is giving me more visibility with the recruiters!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;built-a-website-for-a-friend&#34;&gt;Built a website for a friend.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tested my skills in building and launching a portfolio website from scratch. Out of nowhere, one of my friends asked me if someone could help him set up a website for his manufacturing company. I just took it upon myself and set up a basic website. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://marvelroctec.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Here’s the link&lt;/a&gt;. The website is still a work in progress but setting this up in just one day gave me a reassurance that I can do new things if I will. I wouldn’t have done this if not for the layoff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These are small but great things.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adversities throw you into deep waters and it is in these deep waters that you discover great things which you otherwise wouldn’t have. The layoff which seemed like a setback actually helped me discover my older self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Completing this ‘long-pending’ list of activities felt liberating and helped me ‘reset.’ I am calling it a reset because I used to do these activities earlier before I got ‘too busy’ or just got ‘too lazy’ and this break helped me reset back to myself. And rediscovering your older self sometimes feels liberating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although you should convert every setback into an opportunity it should not always take a major setback to do what feels liberating to you. You don’t want to burn your fingers every time you want to do something great. You can simply do great things all the time, and occasionally burn your fingers in that pursuit. And it should be a constant pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have now slowly moved into the new ‘Normal’ after the reset, slowly fitting all these fulfilling activities into my routine - in some form or the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, the idea is not to get overwhelmed by these additional sets of tasks/activities but to embrace them and fit them into the daily routine to the best of your ability, with a lot of diligence and conviction to complete them and not leave them midway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Did you ever find yourself in such situations? What makes you feel liberated? What fulfilling activity did you do recently?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let me know!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Value of Defaults</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/the-value-of-defaults/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 16:16:32 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/the-value-of-defaults/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/the-value-of-defaults/defaults-resized.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The Value of Defaults" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;lets-start-with-a-story&#34;&gt;Let’s start with a story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have recently migrated from an Android smartphone to an iPhone. One stark difference I saw between the both of them was in their default settings. This difference was stark yet so subtle that it’s hard to realise unless you pay attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diving into the story… I remember when I was using the Android smartphone I had to follow this routine of going through my notifications at the end of the day, clearing off the irrelevant ones to figure out if anything needed my attention. However, I was often swindled by some irrelevant notification which should not have had my attention. I then, without any intention, spent the next hour or two browsing random Apps which otherwise did not provide any value to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After an hour-long unproductive exercise, I used to convince myself that it was probably worth spending that time. “&lt;em&gt;I got relaxed. Great stress-buster&lt;/em&gt;,” I gave false assurance to myself. The particularly impermissible part about this was this happened day after day, every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, after I switched to the iPhone, I spend less time “&lt;em&gt;relaxing&lt;/em&gt;” myself going through irrelevant notifications or browsing unnecessary Apps. I know exactly which notifications need my attention and when. &lt;em&gt;How? you might ask.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-does-iphone-do-it&#34;&gt;How does iPhone do it?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite simple actually. When a new App is installed on an iPhone, the Notifications preference is asked by default. It asks you how you want to receive the notifications from that App and gives you three options to choose from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow immediately&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This allows the App to deliver the notifications immediately. This could be used for the ones which are important and require your attention immediately&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allow in schedule&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a brilliant notification feature in iPhone, one that I love the most. If this is selected, the notifications will be delivered &lt;strong&gt;only as per the schedule you set&lt;/strong&gt; - like at 8 PM in the night and you won’t be interrupted in the middle of the day. Could be used for the ones which are important but do not need immediate attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Allow&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This simply does not deliver any notifications from the App. Could be used for the ones that are not important and do not need any immediate attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iphone-and-its-many-defaults&#34;&gt;iPhone and its many defaults&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just for notifications, the iPhone comes with many other default settings which might not even have occurred to the user, but iPhone solves it and that&amp;rsquo;s the beauty of a great product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Allow location permission’ is disabled by default on iPhone for all Apps. Apps ask for permission before accessing the location. On the contrary, location permission is enabled by default on an Android. So, Android doesn&amp;rsquo;t give location privacy - again for the same reason that nobody wants to take that extra effort to change the default preference&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;‘Screentime’ is turned on by default: iPhone calculates the ‘Screentime’ - time spent on each App and gives you a summary of it on a daily/weekly/monthly basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When an iPhone is put on silent, it does not vibrate too: ‘Vibrate on silent’ is disabled by default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It automatically turns off the Hotspot, if it is not in use for a long time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If WiFi/Bluetooth are turned off before going to bed, iPhone turns them on by default the next day morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It suggests a &amp;lsquo;Do Not Disturb setup by default for your sleeping hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-lazy-man--his-mind&#34;&gt;The lazy man &amp;amp; his mind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default way of asking you to choose any preference ensures that it IS set. It makes the entire exercise of changing settings very smooth and less stressful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Notifications preference was not set at the time of installation of an App, it most likely won’t be changed later anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking any initiative (changing Notification preferences in this case) comes with a high amount of friction because it requires you to spend your energy. But you, as a human, are inherently wired to conserve energy as part of our evolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You do not exactly know what needs to be done to change the notification settings because neither is it something that you do very often nor are you trained on it. And you don&amp;rsquo;t do it, because you don&amp;rsquo;t know it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third, you subconsciously don’t want to spend your effort on something that snatches away your right to “&lt;em&gt;relaxation&lt;/em&gt;.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fourth, if you get irrelevant notifications daily from not just one, not just two, but from many Applications, you know that you need to turn off the notification for each one of them! “&lt;em&gt;Turning off notifications for one App itself seems a big task, now you’re asking me to turn them off for all of them? It is not happening. I rather not turn off any&lt;/em&gt;,” thinks the mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asking the Notifications preference to be set by default on an iPhone ensures that I go ahead and set the preference. Without this default nudge, I bet, I would have never gone into changing the App notification settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-defaults-do-anyway&#34;&gt;What do &amp;lsquo;defaults&amp;rsquo; do, anyway?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These defaults, though very trivial and minute, simplify the things we do every day and that makes THE difference in the long run. It is hard to understand how they help you if you have something by default because you get to do things without much effort, sometimes without you even noticing them and hence you hardly appreciate their value. You generally tend to value something if it was difficult for you, if it was something noticeable or if you had spent a considerable amount of time or money on it. The greater the loss, the greater the perceived value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When something happens by default, you assume that it was ought to happen. You don’t tend to appreciate how difficult it must have been for something to happen by default. You do not realise how different things would have been in the absence of that ‘default.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at an examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;making-life-easy-at-home&#34;&gt;Making life easy at home&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was at home in Hyderabad, my mother was the one taking care of the chores, preparing food, ensuring I take care of my health and well-being and doing everything to keep the household together. And now, after marriage, my wife helps me with most of these things though she also is a working employee. (Side note: I am grateful for the women in my life!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I realise the importance and significance of getting these things done by default, without my notice and realisation. Because I know that my stay in Bengaluru was a struggle as a bachelor when these things were not taken care of by default. When things happen by default, you don’t give it a damn. Remove the default and life goes haywire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-the-right-defaults&#34;&gt;Setting the right defaults&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about it, is there anything that is happening with you that is making your life easy? You may not realise them immediately, but I am sure there are plenty of things that are happening in your life without your intervention which are keeping your peace of mind. Those are your defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting the right defaults leads to a great design of the product. And the same thing applies to life too. We come across defaults in our day-to-day life also. They go so subdued that they hardly get noticed. But you can take action to set these defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mutual-fund-sips&#34;&gt;Mutual Fund SIPs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, we understand the importance of investing and know that if the money is invested properly, we get a good chance of leading a more harmonious life in the long run. However, investing takes time, effort and skill and we seldom do it. But, the default of ‘monthly SIPs in a mutual fund’ comes in as a saviour. You don’t have to break your head and make a decision every month. By subscribing to a SIP, you are setting a default amount to be invested in a mutual fund. Once set, you don’t have to worry about it (unless the market sentiment looks gloomy for many years to come) and it takes care of the investment for you until you figure out more profitable investment avenues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lunchtime&#34;&gt;Lunchtime&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is setting your lunchtime. Earlier, I was not very punctual in having my lunch. I used to get carried away by my work, be stuck in a meeting or work on something without realising that it was getting late. Having lunch at a fixed time was a luxury, it was very rare! Over time (read: getting old 😛) I realised that not having food on time could lead to potential health issues and I had to figure out a way to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I simply set a default for that. I blocked my calendar for 1 PM - 2 PM every day for lunch, this time was blocked for lunch no matter what. With this, I had set a reminder for myself and because my calendar was blocked, my colleagues refrained from setting up a meeting during that time. I had set a default time for my lunch. And, now, more often than not, I have my lunch between the default 1 PM - 2 PM!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-reason-i-love-uber&#34;&gt;The reason I love Uber&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another product example of how setting a default helps is Uber. Let’s say you use Uber to travel to the office daily. It automatically updates the pickup location by default without you entering it. You just need to select the destination location, and even that would be shown in the suggestions (Uber uses your travel history from a given location and suggests the most recent and frequent destinations). All you need to do is just tap on the suggestion and confirm the booking. This simple determination and suggestion of a location by default is one of the main reasons why I am habituated to opening Uber to find a cab. Only if I do not find a cab on Uber do I open any other App. I was so tuned, that a simple default nudge (of showing/selecting a location) made my life easy and helped me form a habit, without my awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same thing is done by Swiggy as well. It picks the default address based on your location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-else-can-defaults-do&#34;&gt;What else can defaults do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defaults don’t just make life easy. They are particularly used in high-risk situations which could lead to damage to life or property if enough attention is not paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-abcs-of-a-car&#34;&gt;The ABCs of a car&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider the accelerator, the brake and the clutch in a car (the ABCs of a car). Their default positions ensure that torque from the engine is zero, as the accelerator is always in a zero position unless an effort is applied. Similarly, the brake functions such that if more force is applied the car comes to a halt. And the default position of the clutch ensures that the power from the engine is always transmitted to the wheels. Only when the clutch is applied, the transmission stops. Why are their default positions designed that way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look. If either the accelerator or the brake or the clutch were designed oppositely, then their default positions would have resulted in: Accelerator = High, Brakes = Applied, and Clutch = Not transmitting power. This combination is ridiculous because high acceleration when brakes are applied is a contradiction. And having high acceleration as soon as you start the car would make it difficult to control and is life-threatening for you and others. On top, to get the car moving, one would have to do three things together:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press to reduce the acceleration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press to remove the brakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press the clutch to transmit the power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All three at the SAME TIME!!! That would be impossible and nobody would be driving cars. If it was like that, they would have just been vehicles to perform heroics by professional stuntmen in a circus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ease of operation of a car is due to its default controls. One could easily learn these controls, get training and pay little attention to managing their travel needs. Any change or reverse of these default controls, the car would become a museum product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;minimise-your-losses-if-not-maximising-gains&#34;&gt;Minimise your losses, if not maximising gains&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defaults need to be set to ensure that even if no action is taken it minimises the loss. Make it so easy that if you don’t take any decision about something, the default will ensure that it is good enough and your losses are minimised. You also need to set a default when decision-making is bound to consume time and effort, a lack of which might harm you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything where you don’t want to spend your energy, where the returns do not entice you to put in the effort, set defaults. Defaults ensure that you do not go down, they offer stability and guarantee a minimum promise to be delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defaults take a one-time effort, with returns going on for perpetuity till you change them. You will save a lot of headaches by setting defaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Netflix subscription, leaving your car keys on the stand beside your door, automating bill payments, setting an alarm that goes off in the morning - all these are examples of defaults that make your life a tad bit easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-in-it-for-you&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s in it for you?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what default are you going to set today? What value do you see it deliver you?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hooked - book review</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/hooked-book-review/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 20:40:29 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/hooked-book-review/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/hooked-book-review/dice.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hooked - book review" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hooked is one of those books which I would recommend to every aspiring Product Manager. In fact, anyone who is even sparsely connected with human psychology or behaviour should read this. It is a short, quick read and insightful with some clever real-world examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While reading the book, I had collated some important and wow moments in my notepad. I wanted to share them with others and thus this article. Please note that this in no way is the gist of the book! These are just some cool observations I made while reading the book and there could be plenty other cool observations I would have missed. So, I strongly recommend you to read the book than reading this article (yes, I am trying to sabotage myself here! — anything for a good read, right?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/hooked-book-review/hooked.jpeg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;811&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/hooked-book-review/hooked_hucf6db1edf0a21adf1f37daf378f596df_95450_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 480w, https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/hooked-book-review/hooked_hucf6db1edf0a21adf1f37daf378f596df_95450_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A screengrab of the cover page of the original book&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;236&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;568px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have decided to read this article, let’s do it…
The title of the book ‘Hooked’ is indicative of the user behaviour while using some of the current digital products. Products like Facebook, Instagram, TikTok, Spotify, Netflix and plenty others have quite literally hooked their users to use the product again and again. The author, &lt;strong&gt;Nir Eyal&lt;/strong&gt;, explores the reason for this addictive behaviour and simply presents his findings with some cool real-life examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nir Eyal analyses the user behaviour with the help of ‘The Hook Model’ — a habit-forming cycle of Trigger — Action — Variable Reward — Investment. It is this cycle that transforms behaviour into a routine and a habit. It is this cycle that helps us either make or break any habit. (This was described by &lt;strong&gt;James Clear&lt;/strong&gt; in his book ‘Atomic Habits’ as well. Atomic Habits is another fantastic read if you are interested.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/hooked-book-review/the-hook-model.png&#34;
	width=&#34;448&#34;
	height=&#34;517&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/hooked-book-review/the-hook-model_hude045ea56e3619fbb6d744c7f83ba899_34555_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/hooked-book-review/the-hook-model_hude045ea56e3619fbb6d744c7f83ba899_34555_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The hook model&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;86&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;207px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Trigger phase, you are prompted by some trigger— either external or internal. This could be some information or a text message or a notification or a sound or an emotion or a memory from the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-a-facebook-notification-sanjay-and-5-others-have-commented-on-your-post&#34;&gt;Example: A Facebook notification: ‘Sanjay and 5 others have commented on your post’&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, in the Action phase, you take an action as a response to that trigger — something as small as replying to someone or as big as purchasing a house.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-you-like-sanjays-comment&#34;&gt;Example: You like Sanjay’s comment&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third step is about ‘Rewards’. All human actions inherently expect rewards and you take actions in anticipation of rewards. Nir Eyal uses ‘variable rewards’ and not just ‘rewards’ here. This is because you are more likely to form a habit because of the variable component of the reward than the reward itself. I will discuss this in detail later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-you-expect-more-people-to-like-and-comment-and-also-expect-sanjay-to-like-or-comment-on-your-next-post-as-well&#34;&gt;Example: You expect more people to like and comment. And also expect Sanjay to like or comment on your next post as well.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last step in the Hook Model is Investment and it is critical for building habits. You can think of this as an investment of your resource: time or money or emotion etc. The more you invest your resources into a product, the more you value it and more likely are you to go back to it again. In other words, your perceived value of a product increases as you spend more time on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think about it, all these ‘addictive’ products try to keep you glued to them for as long as possible! And you tend to go back to using the product again with the slightest of a trigger because you have already invested much of your time or money or emotion into it, you want to see how that investment has shaped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-as-you-liked-sanjays-comment-you-are-drawn-to-another-post-by-a-mutual-friend-of-yours-and-sanjays-you-click-that-and-bang--you-enter-the-world-of-infinite-scroll-and-auto-play-videos-and-before-you-notice-you-have-already-spent-the-last-25min-watching-an-uncle-dance-some-babies-giggle-and-cats-do-funny-faces&#34;&gt;Example: As you liked Sanjay’s comment, you are drawn to another post by a mutual friend of yours and Sanjay’s. You click that, and bang — you enter the world of infinite scroll and auto-play videos. And before you notice, you have already spent the last 25min watching an uncle dance, some babies giggle and cats do funny faces.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But why is this happening?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lets-look-deeper-into-the-hook-model&#34;&gt;Let’s look deeper into the Hook Model:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;triggers&#34;&gt;Triggers&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two kinds of triggers for taking any action: &lt;strong&gt;external and internal.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;External Triggers:&lt;/strong&gt;
External Triggers are those which are caused by an external stimulus, by some outside force or outside substance. Businesses use different types of external triggers prompting a user to take action :\&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paid trigger.&lt;/strong&gt; Example: Spotify’s advertises for its new video podcasts. This makes you curious to check that out because you know that Spotify is a music streaming application and this advertisement about video podcasts surprises you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earned trigger.&lt;/strong&gt; A typical PR or a media mention. Example: Elon Musk’s tweet about Signal: ‘Use Signal’ caused mass hysteria and many started to use Signal after that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationship trigger.&lt;/strong&gt; Example: Your friend tells you about how cool the new ‘FaceApp’ is and you feel like trying it once
Owned trigger. A typical subscription, like that of a newsletter or a club membership, or an App icon on the phone. Example: You subscribed to Medium and open it once a week as Medium sends you an email about a new viral article every week. Or you frequently open WhatsApp on your phone just because the App icon is visible to you on your home screen. Owned triggers increase the repeat engagement of the user. Without owned triggers, it is difficult to form a habit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Triggers:&lt;/strong&gt;
Human emotions are the internal triggers that prompt the user to take an action. More often than not, negative emotions drive the user to spontaneously take an action than positive emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Negative Emotions:&lt;/strong&gt; boredom, fear, loneliness, frustration, confusion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive Emotions:&lt;/strong&gt; happiness, motivation, compassion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-now-and-then-when-you-feel-like-you-are-bored-you-tend-to-open-facebook-or-youtube-just-to-check-whats-going-on-without-any-external-trigger&#34;&gt;Example: Now and then when you feel like you are bored, you tend to open Facebook or Youtube just to check what’s going on, without any external trigger.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;New habits are sparked by external triggers, but the associations with internal triggers are what keeps them hooked to the product. Designers take special care in ensuring that internal triggers are taken care in the user journey with the product.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;rewards&#34;&gt;Rewards&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rewards create a dopamine surge in the brain. Dopamine, often referred to as the pleasure hormone, plays a vital role in how we feel. It helps us strive, focus and find things interesting. Higher the dopamine surge, higher the pleasure. As dopamine gets released, we surpass the brain’s decision and judgement areas and activate the parts associated with want and desire. So, if dopamine is released by doing some action then that action is directly associated with our wants and desires. And because of this association we want to do that action again in anticipation of the reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And introducing variability in rewards simply multiplies this effect. In addition, variability in rewards activates the nucleus accumbens region in our brain and spikes the levels of the neurotransmitter Dopamine, driving our hungry search for rewards further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the products use this rewarding mechanism to keep the users glued. There three types of variable rewards which Product Designers incorporate in their designs: Reward bythe Tribe, Reward by the Hunt, Reward by the Self&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tribe:&lt;/strong&gt; We look for rewards in the form of social recognition or acceptance from our tribe, from those who are like us. We are more likely to alter our behaviours and beliefs if we see others who are more like ourselves being rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-likes-and-comments-on-facebook-upvotes-and-badges-on-stackoverflow&#34;&gt;Example: Likes and comments on Facebook, upvotes and badges on Stackoverflow&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hunt:&lt;/strong&gt; Variable reward which is given after the completion of a task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-the-outcome-on-the-gambling-machine-after-spinning-it-total-points-accumulated-after-playing-a-round-of-candy-crush&#34;&gt;Example: The outcome on the gambling machine after spinning it, total points accumulated after playing a round of Candy Crush&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a very personal form of gratification. These are fueled by intrinsic motivation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-you-feel-happy-about-3-kills-in-pubg-today-compared-to-only-1-kill-yesterday&#34;&gt;Example: You feel happy about 3 kills in PUBG today compared to only 1 kill yesterday&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies spend a lot of time and effort in designing the perfect model of variable rewards. Variable rewards are not some magic fairy dust to sprinkle on the products, they are carefully designed considering why a particular user uses a product and what kind of variable reward aligns with the user’s internal triggers and motivations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings us to the last step in the Hook Model: &lt;strong&gt;Investments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;investments&#34;&gt;Investments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above variable rewards combined with the investment of user’s time and effort into the product makes the user come back to the product again and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons why we tend to go back to the product again and again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We tend to value things more which we’ve created/put in our efforts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We tend to repeat our past behaviours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tend to go back to the same product again and again because we have already invested our time or money or effort or emotions into it. The idea behind the investment phase is to leverage a user’s belief that the service will get better over time with further use and personal investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some examples of different investments users make:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content: Youtube, TikTok, Facebook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data: Linkedin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge: Medium, Substack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotions: Instagram Stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Money: Netflix Premium, Spotify Premium&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is pretty much this habit-forming cycle of Trigger-Action-Variable Reward-Investment that keeps us hooked to a particular product and makes us go back to it again and again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the rest of the article, you can find some related heuristics about this habit-forming cycle. In no particular order, I have provided some insights drawn in bits and pieces from the book: some experiments, theories and anecdotes related to this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;foggs-model-for-human-behaviour&#34;&gt;Fogg’s Model for human behaviour:**&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Fogg’s model, any user behaviour depends on three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User’s motivation to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User’s ability to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User’s trigger to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, Fogg represents this by equation B = MAT. So, the behaviour is a product of Motivation, Ability and Trigger. If any of these is not present or is insufficient then the user will not cross the line to take an action and thus not form a habit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motivation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Three Core Motivators in human beings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek pleasure and avoid pain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek hope and avoid fear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek social acceptance and avoid rejection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The factors that influence the ability to do a task are time, money, physical effort, mental effort, social acceptance, non-routineness of a task. It is found that the product designers focus on easing the scarciest resource at the moment of deciding to do a task or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influencing behaviour by reducing the effort required to act is more effective than increasing someone’s desire to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-you-will-find-that-the-buy-now-button-on-amazon-will-be-of-same-colour-shape-and-design-across-the-website-this-is-to-reduce-the-mental-effort-by-the-user-to-process-what-that-button-means-you-need-to-process-it-only-once-when-you-visit-amazon-for-the-first-time-every-other-time-you-know-what-that-button-means-and-hence-you-are-eased-of-that-mental-effort&#34;&gt;Example: You will find that the ‘Buy Now’ button on Amazon will be of same colour, shape and design across the website. This is to reduce the mental effort by the user to process what that button means. You need to process it only once, when you visit Amazon for the first time. Every other time, you know what that button means and hence you are eased of that mental effort.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trigger:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I discussed Triggers earlier in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-common-heuristics&#34;&gt;Other Common Heuristics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some common heuristics which businesses typically make use of to trigger behaviours. As we see below, these heuristics are designed so that people make split-second decisions every day and yet remain unaware of how they are influenced in making those decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The scarcity effect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
People associate more value to the things that are scarce. A study by Worchel, Lee, and Adewole showed that the perceived value of scarcer items was more than the items in abundance, though the items were the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-this-effect-is-used-by-online-retailers-like-amazon-only-14-items-in-the-stock&#34;&gt;Example: This effect is used by online retailers like Amazon: ‘Only 14 items in the stock.’&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another cool point in this context is that the perceived value increases as the product once abundant gradually becomes scarce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-this-is-seen-in-tele-shopping-where-products-are-sold-on-tv-in-this-the-product-advertised-will-start-with-qty-1000-available-and-the-number-is-gradually-reduced-as-the-number-reduces-from-1000-to-700-to-500-the-viewers-attach-more-value-to-the-product-and-tend-to-place-the-order&#34;&gt;Example: This is seen in Tele Shopping where products are sold on TV. In this, the product advertised will start with ‘Qty: 1000 available’ and the number is gradually reduced. As the number reduces from 1000 to 700 to 500, the viewers attach more value to the product and tend to place the order.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Anchoring Effect:&lt;/strong&gt;
We get transfixed to something that is shown to us directly. We tend to believe it to be true on instinct and do not notice other things happening around us or question other things — we are too lazy to pay attention or question our instincts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-you-walk-into-a-shopping-mall-and-see-the-50-off-signboard-and-instinctively-go-towards-that-you-rarely-question-what-that-50-off-actually-means-in-most-cases-50-off-is-given-as-part-of-a-clearance-sale-on-old-products-or-on-some-other-products-which-you-wouldnt-otherwise-purchase-the-idea-here-is-to-get-your-foot-in-the-door-once-there-the-shopkeeper-will-try-and-sell-other-costly-products-to-you&#34;&gt;Example: You walk into a shopping mall and see the ‘50% Off’ signboard and instinctively go towards that. You rarely question what that 50% Off actually means. In most cases, 50% Off is given as part of a clearance sale on old products or on some other products which you wouldn’t otherwise purchase. The idea here is to get your foot in the door. Once there, the shopkeeper will try and sell other ‘costly’ products to you.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Endowed Progress Effect:&lt;/strong&gt;
People tend to put more effort to reach a goal if they believe that they have made progress or are making progress towards that goal. It is a phenomenon that increases motivation as people believe that they can achieve the goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-to-make-more-people-update-their-profile-linkedin-uses-the-profile-strength-progress-bar-as-you-notice-that-your-profile-is-only-50-complete-you-intrinsically-yearn-to-fill-in-more-details-and-hit-a-higher-number-on-the-progress-bar&#34;&gt;Example: To make more people update their profile, Linkedin uses the profile strength progress bar. As you notice that your profile is only 50% complete, you intrinsically yearn to fill in more details and hit a higher number on the progress bar.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Framing Effect:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The environment in which a product or value is delivered affects the way the value is perceived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-a-musician-playing-in-a-paid-concert-will-be-valued-more-compared-to-the-same-musician-playing-in-a-subway-for-free-another-example-the-same-wine-from-a-bottle-tagged-1000-will-taste-better-than-that-from-a-bottle-tagged-100&#34;&gt;Example: A musician playing in a paid concert will be valued more compared to the same musician playing in a subway for free. Another example, the same wine from a bottle tagged $1,000 will taste better than that from a bottle tagged $100!&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more about the &lt;strong&gt;Framing effect&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/framing-effect&#34; &gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; that some of the examples I mentioned above are not from the book but are my personal examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings to the end of the article. Hope you liked it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you for reading! 🙏🏼&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👍🏼 ➡️ If you liked it, please share it with others who might find it interesting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;💬 Also, please leave your comment or feedback below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People - book review</title>
        <link>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people-book-review/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:57:05 +0530</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people-book-review/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people-book-review/7-habits.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People - book review" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of us either in the school, or at work, or in any of the great speeches would have heard of the difference between effectiveness and efficiency. Give it a thought, pause for a minute and think about what effectiveness is and what efficiency is? Think of your own daily activities… can you name at least one activity in which you are very effective and one activity in which you are very efficient? What difference does that make?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, in very simple terms, being effective is doing the ‘right’ thing and being efficient is doing the thing ‘rightly’. So, it, essentially, is the purpose that differentiates effectiveness from efficiency. Assume you are a team leader, you are effective only when you and your team is aligned to the company’s vision, mission and goals — more the alignment more effective you will be. If you are not aligned with the vision, mission, and goals then you are not effective, all your efforts are of no use no matter how good you are at doing what you do. On the other hand, you are efficient if you are good at doing what you do, doesn’t really matter if it is important, or if it solves any problem at all. You are efficient in doing something if you are good at it irrespective of it being useful or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, assume you work in a company which manufactures ‘Moulded Dies’. If you make 1000 dies a day, you may be the most efficient person in the company to make dies. But you are completely ineffective if you make circular dies while the company wanted you to make square dies. All your efforts are waste and do not solve any problem, there is no purpose to what you do. In another example, a tablet for headache is ineffective if you use it if you have a stomach ache. No matter how many tablets you eat, unless you take the right tablet you will not be cured of the ailment. So, effectiveness is determined by taking the final goal/result into consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, in my own case, I have taken a resolution to read 24 books this year. I will be fully efficient in reading 24 books if I complete reading all of them. But, will I be effective? I will be effective if I read good books and take lessons from those books rather than just reading them. As a matter of fact, I have realized that ‘24 books a year’ is quite some benchmark and I am falling short by a large margin! So, my efficiency has gone for a toss. However, I think, as I am able to take lessons from these books I am getting better at being effective in my life, each page at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, stop for a moment. Think. Why are you doing what you are doing? Is that what you really should be doing or are you doing it because you are told to do so? Is that what your goal is? Is that what you seek in your life? Is that your ultimate purpose? In our lives, we are all paid for being efficient, for being good at what we do. In fact, we strive to be the best in the business. And someone else is paying for it because someone sees that you are effective for him/her… you are giving them the results they want. But, are you giving yourself the results you want? Are you really effective for yourself?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people-book-review/motivation2.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1920&#34;
	height=&#34;819&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people-book-review/motivation2_hu7629922d0e44c6a10abb74369325616f_91299_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://www.arjunuvacha.com/p/the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people-book-review/motivation2_hu7629922d0e44c6a10abb74369325616f_91299_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;234&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;562px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephen R Covey&lt;/strong&gt; is widely known for his famous book — &amp;ldquo;The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People&amp;rdquo;. I finished reading the book recently and it has a great impact on how I think, how I talk and everything I do. So, here I am, sharing my views and lessons from the book. These are either the habits Stephen described in detail in the book or the habits that I seek to inculcate in my life. I do not really intend to review the book, as this book doesn’t require any review and it just is a great book for everyone out there who aspires to become a better self, every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we say habits, all we recollect are the typical habits like getting up early in the morning, or reading a newspaper regularly or greeting your colleagues, or being punctual always, etc. These are just behavioral habits which can be practiced and displayed at a physical level and may not necessarily reflect a change or improvement at a deeper level. A level at which you truly believe in displaying them, and have complete integrity between your belief and actions. This change requires a stronger will and takes a huge character-building exercise. The 7 habits described by Stephen use that character-building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen uses the terms ‘Personal Ethics’ and ‘Character Ethics’; personal ethics are the ethical standards which are set to keep your behavior or personality in check. Behavioral or personality traits are visible to others and you rely on others’ feedback to measure your progress or improvement. These are all outward signs and projections others can notice. You, however, may not have a strong desire internally to keep up to these standards or you may lose interest if others stop giving you the feedback. These can be easily affected if they do not yield the required results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, assume you determine to go to the gym regularly. You start going to the gym for 15 days and after 15 days if you notice that there is no change in your physique or if nobody has appreciated you for your efforts to go to the gym daily, you will lose all the interest and desire you had in the beginning and you stop going to gym. There was no real desire for self-improvement, only an attempt for outwardly change for immediate results to continue further. If results are not seen, you may never continue and no habit is formed. On the contrary, habits are formed by doing them, again and again, every day, and they then drive results, not the other way round. This requires a deep resolution that gets etched in your character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Character ethics are your standards which you truly believe in. They are not set at a superficial physical level. They are basic principles of effective living and people can experience true success and happiness when they integrate these basic principles into their character. These principles are like guiding light, like lighthouses, they give direction and show the destination. These are the basic principles like integrity, humility, patience, simplicity, modesty, etc. It may sound very absurd and you may even think how can these help form habits! But, your character, fundamentally, influences everything you do — influences others and the environment around you. Your deep motives manifest into reality. So, unless there is a resolution to correct yourself deep down, at a fundamental level, you cannot form a habit that will be sustainable and help you experience true success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is only after you resolve yourself at an inner level, which is in your complete control, will you be able to move further and work on resolving other external factors which are not in your complete control, but which can be influenced. If you yourself are fundamentally flawed, without any respect to your own set of ethics, then you can never expect others to respect you. Without this respect and influence, you lose the sanctity in the interpersonal relationships and never be able to be effective which involves others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interpersonal relationship is as much important as your own ability to do things, as your effectiveness is not just a function of how you do things. In this world of interpersonal dependence, your effectiveness is fundamentally a function of you and other factors around you. In fact, in many cases, the factors around you play a major role to determine your effectiveness and if you can influence these factors around you, you can create synergy and be more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Stephen’s own words, you have two circles you find yourself in. The first is the ‘Circle of Concern’ and the second is the ‘Circle of Influence’. The circle of concern is where the problem is, where there is constant pain and worry. Unable to meet the targets is a concern for a sales manager or a child playing too much video game is a concern for a parent. In every difficult situation, you find yourself trapped in a circle of concern and deeply absorbed in the nuances of the problem. By being engrossed in the circle, you do not solve the problem. It only adds to the worry you already have and doesn’t take you away from it. However, solving this problem requires a completely new paradigm, which Stephen calls as ‘Circle of Influence’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circle of influence is where you have your influence, where you can actually control things which can affect your circle of concern and thereby solve the problem. You cannot really solve a problem by focusing on the problem, you can only solve it by focusing on the solution. It may sound very rudimentary and cliched, but this needs a completely different mindset — a mindset which is positive, problem-solving, creative, open for change, open for suggestions, and open for trial and failure. It takes a lot of courage to work with this mindset, as you may not necessarily see light at the end of the tunnel, but you stay positive and keep moving. By working in your circle of influence, you make positive progress. You know that you are working on a solution and any small positive effect will boost your confidence. Your confidence will be a cause for more progress leading to more positive effect. This builds a positive spiral and over time, you make so much progress that you don’t realize you are already out of the problem and take one positive step towards being effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you work on the things you can control, things you can influence, you will be able to solve the problems in the circle of concern and eventually you notice that the circle of concern becomes smaller and smaller. So, you have to work in the circle of influence and grow your circle of influence. Bigger the circle, better will be your chances to be more effective.
You are the center of the circle of influence. You form the essential core. As mentioned earlier, you can only influence others if they trust you, if they respect you and if they find you credible. So, it is important that you win yourself first — make yourself credible, before you make an attempt to win others or influence others. Stephen calls this ‘Private Victory’. Private Victory is the starting point of gaining others’ trust. And only Private Victory can lead to ‘Public Victory’, winning others. Private Victory always precedes Public Victory. No individual would show any interest in you or respect you if you don’t do it yourself. Effectiveness always starts with Private Victory, followed by Public Victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen lays out the 7 habits with the first 3 focusing on Private Victory, the second 3 focusing on Public Victory and the last one on how to get better at these habits. With the context given above, let us look at these 7 habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these habits are briefly given below. I wrote them in the shortest way possible. If you want to read them in detail, you must read the book. It is worth its time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;habit-1-be-proactive&#34;&gt;Habit 1: Be proactive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being proactive is often confused with being fast or being quick. Being fast or quick is just one part of it. You are truly proactive if you are responsible and reliable. You make conscious efforts to ensure that are on top of the things which are expected from you. By doing so, you tend to be fast and quick. For example, assume you work in an IT firm and your client is a big deal for your company. Your team is working on a product and the release date is just a week away. You are NOT proactive if you do not really care about the quality and longevity of the product. You may just ensure that the product is working well in all test cases. But being proactive would mean, you take the complete responsibility of the product — even those aspects which otherwise would not be evident to the client. In the worst case, you will proactively communicate to the client about all the ‘invisible’ aspects of the product. But, never find discomfort in telling the truth, rather find comfort in not hiding anything. Taking responsibility is a huge mindset makeover. You do not usually own anything unless you are absolutely convinced about yourself and your ability to take ownership. And taking ownership in everything you do keeps you on top of things and tests your ability to take them to closure. You do not complain about how others were responsible for your failure. You take the beating if you fail and enjoy the fruit if you succeed. You own the failure as much as you own the success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;habit-2-start-with-the-end-in-the-mind&#34;&gt;Habit 2: Start with the end in the mind&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with the end in the mind means that you are clear with what your expectations of the end outcome are. You know exactly what you want. You know the outcome you are working for. This outcome is something that you feel very well connected to. This outcome could be an immediate activity you are working on, or a short term goal of a year or a long term goal of 20 years or anything which you do. The idea is, unless you know what you are working for, you cannot prepare yourself for it and you may not be moving in the right direction to complete it. In many cases, the outcome you intend is only possible with right efforts from different people around you and you cannot ensure that all are moving in the right direction if you are not clear of what you want! Without having any goal or end result in mind is like a cat chasing its tail — the cat may find itself busy but is utterly pointless for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;habit-3-prioritize&#34;&gt;Habit 3: Prioritize&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen very well quotes: “People prioritize their schedules, but in fact, they should schedule their priorities”. Prioritizing things has been one main focus of many people who try to be more effective. However, most of these ‘prioritization’s are on urgent items, burning issues, critical concerns, unexpected escalations, etc. It is understandable that which cannot be postponed, which needs immediate attention should be treated with priority. But, could these cases be avoided? In most of the cases, it is yes! We generally do not tend to focus on fixing a severe problem with long term solution — so the problem repeats itself and consumes our ‘urgent’ time. We do not spend time on creating a robust system, leaving loopholes which require your attention time and again. If you are a process manager, you can relate to how important setting a good process is. If you do not spend enough time creating a foolproof process, you regret spending unimaginably more time fixing smaller issues which occur at a later point in time. This is an ineffective way of doing things though you may be spending your time in firefighting doing something which is both important and urgent. However, you could have avoided this situation if you had spent enough time doing something which was important but not urgent — setting up the process in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This takes us to the second habit — start with the end in your mind. If you think long and start early, you will be working on something which is important but not urgent. But over time, you will have a robust process in place which will avoid all minor issues which do not need your attention. So, the ideal way of doing things is spending more time on ‘Important but not urgent’ activities. Initially, it will be challenging to move away from doing ‘important and urgent’ activities to ‘important but not urgent activities’, but as long as you have your end goal in mind you will consider the challenges unimportant or work to resolve them. As you do more of ‘important but not urgent’ activities, you notice that your ‘important and urgent’ bucket of activities becomes smaller and smaller and that is the ideal way you can be more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;habit-4-think-win-win&#34;&gt;Habit 4: Think win-win&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the majority of your activities, you deal with people either directly or indirectly. And their involvement determines your effectiveness. You cannot win everything with your effort alone. You need others also to support you, in your cause. But, in order to win, you tend to disregard others and think only about how you can win without much concern about others. This will hamper your relationship with others and may not be the most effective way of doing things in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ‘win-win’ thinking comes from an abundance mentality. Abundance mentality says that there is enough cake for both the parties to take away. Abundance mentality creates broader and bigger platforms for discussions for both the parties and you both would discover newer ways and newer ideas of doing things which otherwise did not exist. Also, it is not possible to find everyone who is happy with the ‘win-win’ model of working. There are people who only work with ‘lose-win’ mentality — where they win and you lose. The best way in such cases is you convince the other person for a ‘win-win’ deal, else walk away. There is no use wasting your time when you know that it is not the most effective way of doing things in the long run. It will collapse one day. So, refrain from it from the beginning only. At the same time, do not press on others for a ‘win-lose’ deal — this will again hamper your relationship on the long run. Refrain from it as well. Always think ‘win-win’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;habit-5-seek-first-to-understand-than-to-be-understood&#34;&gt;Habit 5: Seek first to understand than to be understood&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding others is what we think we do, but seldom do it. It is only our perception that we have understood the other person well. It takes an unbelievably long time to actually understand the other person. And it is very much essential that we build this understanding. We do not listen well to understand completely, we listen only to respond back. In our hurry to make others understand, we lose our ability to understand others. We all have our own set of presumptions, our own ideals, our own principles and our own way of looking at things. But to understand the other person well, you need to first know their complete point of view, the reason for such a point of view. Only after you know that will you be able to understand. Only when you understand others will you be able to consider their true point of view and accommodate in your thinking and thereby comprehensively building a more accurate ‘win-win’ situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, stop listening to respond and start listening to understand and empathize. Listen, not just by words, but by tone, mannerisms, body language, and all aspects of non-verbal communication. Everything speaks if you listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;habit-6-synergize&#34;&gt;Habit 6: Synergize&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synergy means that the whole is greater than the sum of individual parts. Assume that in a manufacturing company, two products X and Y are sold at ₹100 and ₹200 respectively. The company then uses some of its techniques to combine X and Y and creates a new product that can be sold at ₹500. Here, an additional value of ₹200 is created! This is synergy. Synergy doesn’t only happen in physical entities or companies. The reason synergy existed in the manufacturing company above is because different people have come together and created a new product. So, synergy can be created when different people come together with a mindset to create something more than what is existing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order for you to be more effective, you need to synergize with others. Only when this happens will you be able to do more with less — less time, less money… fewer resources and fewer resources are a crucial part of the effectiveness equation. With this synergistic way of doing things in the right direction, you will be more effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;habit-7-sharpen-your-saw&#34;&gt;Habit 7: Sharpen your saw&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being effective is a never-ending process. There is always more that you can do of yourself, for yourself. It needs an open mind to learn new things, new ways, meet new people and do new things. You need to sharpen your saw, keep getting better at your habits in the area of Private Victory as well as in the area of Public Victory. Visit them, every day and try to be better the next day. It is the only way forward to be more effective. You don’t postpone it to tomorrow, you do it today.
With these, I leave you with the 7 Habits I read in the book and find useful in building an effective lifestyle — a minute improvement each day, every day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you for reading! 🙏🏼&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👍🏼 ➡️ If you liked it, please share it with others who might find it interesting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;💬 Also, please leave your comment or feedback below.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
